Frank Morton Jones Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Frank Morton Jones Archives
1906-1951
ENTAR.001877
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
10
Archives of Frank Morton Jones
Jones, Frank M., 1869-22/05/1962
Biographical Sketch
1869-1962 Frank Morton Jones Frank was a 20th century naturalist, investigating primarily entomology, particularly Lepidoptera and the insects associated with the pitcher plant family Sarraceniaceae. In 1954 Frank Morton Jones donated a bulk of his library, archival material, and collection to the Yale Peabody Museum.
Description of the Material
The Archives of Frank Morton Jones were donated to the Yale Peabody Museum in 1954.
Connecticut; Delaware; Correspondence; Books; Locality information; Research notes; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Austin, R.M. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 5+., 1918; 002491
  - Eastwood, Alice. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 5+., 1918-1920; 002490
  - Ferguson, M.J. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 5+., 1918-1920; 002496
  - Hail, M.A. Some via Herbert F Hail. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 25+., 1918-1932; 002489
  - Hall, H.M. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 5+., 1918-1920; 002495
  - Heller, A.A. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 10+., 1914-1918; 002492
  - Hepburn, Joseph. Correspondence between Frank Martin Jones and Joeseph Hepburn. EST number of items = 100+., 1917-1918; 002505
  - Jepson, W.L. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 2., 1930; 002497
  - Lloyd, Francis E. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 10+., 1939-1940; 002487
  - Lumen. Related to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 1., 1918; 002500
  - Macfarlane, John M. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 25+., 1906-1933; 002488
  - Nichols, H.B. Related to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 2., 1914-1918; 002502
  - Pendleton, George M. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 10+., 1914-1918; 002493
  - Pennell, F.W. EST number of items = 3., 1951; 002499
  - Poulton, Edward. Correspondence between Frank Martin Jones and Sir Edward Poulton of the Royal Entomological Society. Many papers mailed back and forth. EST number of items = 50+., 1931-1938; 002506
  - Steckbeck, Walter. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 3., 1929-1951; 002498
  - Stratton, L.J. Related to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 1., 1918; 002503
  - Sweetster, A. R. Much relating to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 5+., 1921-1924; 002494
  - Unknown. Correspondence to Frank Martin Jones with either no name or an illegible signature. EST number of items =5+., 002504
  - Wickes, H.O. Related to darlingtonia. EST number of items = 1., 1918; 002501
- Taxon Notes, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Notes from research, field work, experiments etc on different Taxa.
  - Ants & Insectivorous Plants., 1907-1926; 002510
  - Aphiochaeta Iroquoiana., 002518
  - Aphiochaeta Minor., 002529
  - Botanobia Darlingtoniae., 002530
  - Dohrniphora Venusta., 002532
  - Drosera & Dionaea., 1929; 002511
  - Expeiments & Tests., 002516
  - Exyra Fax Grt., 002535
  - Exyra Grote., 002534
  - Exyra Ridingsii., 002528
  - Exyra Semicrocea., 002527
  - Flower Stem Borers in Scarracenia., 002512
  - Isodontia Harrisi Ferdald., 002521
  - Metriocnemus Edwards I Jones., 002523
  - Metriocnemus Knabi., 002522
  - Neosciara Macfarlanei Jones., 002524
  - Neosciara Macfarlanei., 002525
  - North American Sarracenia., Darling., 002517
  - Occasional Associates of Insectivorous Plants., 002514
  - Olethreutes Daeckaena., 002533
  - Papaipema Appassionata., 002526
  - Pollenizers & Captures., 1907-1934; 002513
  - Sarcophaga in Sarracenia., 002519
  - Sketch Maps of Localities., 002515
  - Unidentified Chloropid., 002531
  - Wyeomyia Smithii., 002520
- Published Works, Series III
  - Original Drawings. Original drawings most used or referenced to in published work on pitcher plant insects., 002770
  - Reprints. In Library., 002509